nomeatathlete.com 2019-12-27

# Privacy Policy | No Meat Athlete

No Meat Athlete, LLC (“NMA”) operates NoMeatAthlete.com as well as other domains and media channels. NMA is serious about protecting your data and respecting your privacy. This Privacy Statement explains our views and practices concerning privacy, and how they may pertain to you as a user of our website.

‘You’ or ‘Your’ means you as a participant in, or as a user of, the NoMeatAthlete.com website, any NMA product or service, and/or any affiliated web service. ‘We’ or ‘Our’ or ‘Us’ refers to NMA. ‘Our site’ refers to the NoMeatAthlete.com website, any NMA product or service, and/or any affiliated web service.

**SECTION 1 – WHAT DO WE DO WITH YOUR INFORMATION?**

When you opt-in for access to any downloadable or protected content or purchase a product, we’ll email you about that, plus a short introductory sequence, future blog posts, download opportunities, and other announcements, along with promotional emails. All of our content and promotional materials are related to the topic of plant-based fitness, nutrition, and mindset.

When you purchase something from our site, as part of the buying and selling process, we collect the personal information you give us, such as your name, physical address, phone number, and email address. This enables us to both fulfill and support the products or services you purchase.

When you browse our site, we also automatically receive your computer’s internet protocol (IP) address in order to provide us with information that helps us learn about your browser and operating system so we can better improve the experience for all our users.

From time to time, we might ask you to fill out a survey, or use another means, to gather information about your preferences and interests. We use this data to improve our services and better customize your experience as a NMA reader and/or customer.

Email marketing: With your permission, we may send you emails about new products, free and premium content (e.g. blog posts, podcasts, promotions), special events, as well as content and offers from our partners.

We do not use your data for any other purposes, except those included herein, and will never sell your data to any third-party.

**SECTION 2 – CONSENT**

When you provide us with personal information to complete a transaction, verify your credit card, place an order, arrange for a delivery or return a purchase, we infer that you consent to our collecting it and using it for that specific reason only.

If we ask for your personal information for a secondary reason (e.g. newsletter subscription and marketing messages), we will provide you with an opportunity to withdraw your consent.

You may withdraw your consent at any time by clicking on an “unsubscribe” link which is offered at the bottom of every email we send, and then follow the instructions on the page.

You may also withdraw your consent anytime, by contacting us at support@nomeatathlete.com or calling us at 828.620.0774.

We strive to send only relevant email to people who have demonstrated legitimate interest in receiving our content and promotional emails on plant-based health and fitness topics. We work to identify and exclude from our email broadcasts those users who, though lack of activity (even in the absence of manually opting-out) have demonstrated that they are no longer legitimately interested in our emails.

To this end, we practice list hygiene in several ways, the most important of which is to designate as “inactive” those email subscribers who have not clicked any link in our emails or taken any other action (such as purchasing a product or opting-in via a form on our site) within the previous sixty (60) days. After no more than five (5) attempts to reactivate inactive subscribers by email, we exclude any inactive subscriber located in the European Union (and those in unknown locations) from all future promotional email broadcasts or otherwise emails related to products they have purchased, until such time that subscriber becomes reactivated by purchasing a product, clicking a link in a previously received email, opting-in via a form on our site, or taking some other action which demonstrates consent or legitimate interest.

Further, our software tracks certain aspects of behavior regarding how you interact with our emails and content, such as opens and clicks of emails. We use this data to customize which emails to send you and the content of the emails you receive (for example, we often send promotional messages about certain products to only those subscribers who previously expressed interest in that specific topic by opting-in to download or access free content related to that topic and created with the very purpose of simultaneously delivering value and identifying which users are interested in that specific topic. In this way, we further strive to ensure your legitimate interest in the content of the emails we send you.

**SECTION 3 – DISCLOSURE**

We may disclose your personal information if we are required by law to do so or if you violate our [Terms of Service](https://www.nomeatathlete.com/terms-and-conditions/). Also, if our site is acquired or merged with another company, your information may be transferred to the new owners so that they may continue to offer and support our products and services.

IMPORTANT: We do not sell, rent or otherwise disclose your personal information to any third parties, including but not limited to advertisers, strategic partners, or vendors. Again, we take your privacy very seriously.

**SECTION 4 – DATA STORAGE**

Our shopping cart solution is hosted and managed by Ontraport for digital products and Shopify for physical products (e.g. shirts). They provide us with the online e-commerce platform that allows us to sell our products and services to you.

Your data is stored through Ontraport’s or Shopify’s data storage, databases and the general Ontraport and Shopify applications. They store your data on a secure server behind a firewall.

Payment:

If you choose a direct payment gateway to complete your purchase, then Ontraport or Shopify will store your credit card data. It is encrypted through the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS). Your purchase transaction data is stored only as long as is necessary to complete your purchase transaction. After that is complete, your purchase transaction information is deleted.

All direct payment gateways adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover.

PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of credit card information by our store and its service providers.

NOTE: At no point during the transaction does NMA take custody or store your credit card information. This process is monitored and managed by Ontraport and Shopify, and you can read their terms of service, privacy policy and PCI Compliance information by visiting their sites at: <https://ontraport.com/legal> and https://www.shopify.com/legal

**SECTION 5 – THIRD-PARTY SERVICES**

In general, the third-party providers used by us will only collect, use and disclose your information to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us.

However, certain third-party service providers, such as payment gateways and other payment transaction processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to provide to them for your purchase-related transactions.

For these providers, we recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers.

In particular, remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located a different jurisdiction than either you or us. So if you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the services of a third-party service provider, then your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdiction(s) in which that service provider or its facilities are located.

As an example, if you are located in Canada and your transaction is processed by a payment gateway located in the United States, then your personal information used in completing that transaction may be subject to disclosure under United States legislation, including the Patriot Act.

Once you leave our store’s website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this Privacy Policy or our website’s [Terms of Service](https://www.nomeatathlete.com/terms-and-conditions/).

Links: When you click on links on our site, they may direct you away from our site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites and encourage you to read their privacy statements.

We encourage our readers, customers, and you to review the Privacy Statements and Terms of Service for the web services that we use to serve you: [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policies), [Ontraport](https://ontraport.com/legal), [WordPress](https://en.wordpress.com/tos/), [Web Jam](https://www.webjam.com/privacypolicy), [Sumo](https://sumo.com/tos), [Stripe](https://stripe.com/us/privacy), [Shopify](https://www.shopify.com/legal/terms), [Shipbob](https://www.shipbob.com/terms-and-conditions/#.WvymyogvzIU), [ClickFunnels](https://signup.clickfunnels.com/user-terms), and [Proof](https://useproof.com/terms).

**SECTION 6 – SECURITY**

To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.

If you provide us with your credit card information, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL) and stored with a AES-256 encryption. Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.

**SECTION 7 – COOKIES**

NMA utilizes cookies to create a more customized experience for our users and customers. For example, we use a login cookie so members do not have to re-enter their username and password each time they return to our site. We also use tracking pixels (e.g. Google Analytics, ClickFunnels, Proof, Ontraport) to aid in measuring and tracking where our website traffic is coming from and to track the performance of our site, affiliate products, and sales pages. Finally, we use remarketing pixels from Facebook and Google to aid in customized, targeted follow up advertising.

We encourage our readers, customers, and you to review the Privacy Statements and Terms of Service for the web services that may use pixles or cookies to serve you: [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policies), [Ontraport](https://ontraport.com/legal), [Sumo](https://sumo.com/tos), [Shopify](https://www.shopify.com/legal/terms), [ClickFunnels](https://signup.clickfunnels.com/user-terms), [Google](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en), and [Proof](https://useproof.com/terms).

**SECTION 8 – AGE OF CONSENT**

By using this site, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your state or province of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your state or province of residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use this site.

**SECTION 9 – CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.

**QUESTIONS AND CONTACT INFORMATION**

If you would like to: access, correct, amend or delete any personal information we have about you, register a complaint, or simply want more information contact us at [support@nomeatahlete.com](mailto:support@nomeatahlete.com).
